{
  "reference_number": "10129",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "New Zealand is one of the cleanest countries in the world. Agriculture was put into our ETS when no other country in the world has\n done it. The political reason for this is outlined at the end of the submission."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Methane from agriculure is already at net zero. It is a circular process and scientific studies have verified this. Grass also captures\n\n carbon."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "See Answer number 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "New Zealand should not be governed by a non elected body of bureaucrats. That is communism. See notes at end of submission."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The basis of the New Zealand economy."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "As Question number 4."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "As Question number 4"
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Animals raised by grass fed systems can be a net carbon sink. This is the finding of a new study by scientists from Michigan State\nUniversity that was published in the Agricultural Systems journal. After evaluating adaptive multi-paddock (AMP) grass-fed operations\n\nand grain-fed, feedlot ones, they concluded that AMP grazing has the potential to offset greenhouse gas emissions, while the end\nphase of beef production can actually be a net carbon sink. They reached their conclusion by reviewing past studies and carrying out\nnew research over the course of four years at their Lake Station AgBioResearch Center using herds of more than 200 steers. They\n\nlooked at statistics from the finishing phase, including daily weight gain and carcass weight, and compared it to the carbon dioxide,\nmethane and nitrous oxide from fermentation and digestion, feed production, farm energy use and manure storage. They also\nassessed the carbon losses that arose from soil erosion. I do not like industrialised farming but our beef and sheep farms are virtually\n\nall run on grass fed systems and many of our dairy farms. The worst offenders are Corporate dairy units owned by businessmen\nrather than farmers. The idealogy of Climate change is to change the economic structure of the world. United Nations (U.N.) official\n\nChristina Figueres recently made a stunning statement at a Brussels news conference, admitting that global warming is a hoax.\nFigueres, the executive secretary of the U.N.’s Framework Convention on Climate Change, carefully worded her admission. The\n\ntakeaway is that climate activists aren’t actually trying to save the planet, they’re trying to kill capitalism. Figueres initially stated: “This\nis the first time in the history of mankind that we are setting ourselves the task of intentionally, within a defined period of time, to\nchange the economic development model that has been reigning for at least 150 years, since the Industrial Revolution.” Figueres\n\nreiterates, “This is probably the most difficult task we have ever given ourselves, which is to intentionally transform the economic\ndevelopment model for the first time in human history.” Reported February 2017"
    }
  ]
}
